Archives & Special Collections University of Nebraska–Lincoln Libraries
Carlton and Territa A. Lowenberg Collection on Emily Dickinson and Music
- Scores and Works, 3
  - Oversize scores, Schudel, Thomas, My Life Closed Twice before Its Close, There Came a Wind Like a Bugle, There's a Certain Slant of Light (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Oversize scores, Soule, Edmund, A Book of Emily, or Thirteen Ways of Looking at Miss Dickinson (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Oversize scores, Talma, Louise, One Need Not be a Chamber to be Haunted (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Oversize scores, article, review, Vehar, Persis, Emily D., Three from Emily (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Oversize scores, Waters, James, Goal, Songs of Life (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Oversize scores, Ziffrin, Marilyn J., Symphony for Voice and Orchestra: 'Letters' (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Cassette Tape Recordings, 5
  - Cassettes ED 1-17 (Box 20)
    - Bartow, Jim, An American Poet's Song Book (Box-folder 1.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Setting for voice, trumpet, guitar, contrabass. Performers not identified. "E.D.'s blues" ["Heart! We will forget him"]; "Will there really be a 'morning'?"; "We learned" ["We learned the whole of love"] [Also poems by Paul L Dunbar, Robert Frost, et al.]
    - [Beckler, Stanworth], SRB Dickinson settings (Box-folder 2.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Five Poems of Dickinson, op. 56. Setting for tenor, flute, bassoon, piano, violin. "A Bird" ["A bird came down the walk"]; "Hope" ["'Hope' is the thing with feathers"]; "Brook" ["Have you got a brook in your little heart"]; "Spider" ["The spider holds a silver ball"]; "I went to heaven." Man and Divers Bestiall Companyons, op. 75. Setting for SATB chorus, piano, harpsichord. "The Cricket" ["'Twas later when the summer went"] Four Short Poems of Emily Dickinson, op. 76, #1. Setting for soprano and piano. "Prairie" ["To make a prairie it takes a clover and one bee"]; "Century" ["Funny to be a century"]; "Water" ["Water, is taught by thirst"]; "Parasol" ["The parasol is the umbrella's daughter"]
    - Belet, Brian, Five Songs (Box-folder 3.)
      Noncommerical cassette tape. Setting for lyric coloratura soprano, flute, percussion, piano, viola. 1982 live recording. P1989, Brian Belet. Duration: 15 minutes, 15 seconds. "I died for beauty" [Other poets]
    - Benoliel, Bernard, Eternity-junctions (Box-folder 4.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Premier broadcast performance. Setting for SATB chorus. 1969. BBC Singers; Odaline de la Martinez, conductor. October 27, 1990. "Adrift! A little boat adrift!"; "My river runs to thee"; "I heard a fly buzz when I died"; "To know just how he suffered would be dear"; "Of all the souls that stand create"
    - Bielawa, Herbert, 1973 (Box-folder 5.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. A Dickinson Album, for choir, piano, guitar, troubadour and tape ["The stitching together of the settings is done by the troubadour who, accompanied on his guitar, sings sections of the poem 'Emily Dickinson' by the contemporary poet James Schevill." [Lowenberg, Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, 13.] 1) "The brain" ["The brain within its groove"]; "Much madness" ["Much madness is divinest sense"]; "Winter afternoons" ["There's a certain slant of light"]; "Revolution" ["Revolution is the pod"]; "To fight aloud" ["To fight aloud is very brave"] 2) "Emily Dickinson," by James Scheville
    - Bielawa, Herbert, The Snake and Other Creatures: Settings of Poems by Emily Dickinson, 1973 (Box-folder 6.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. [Composed 1987 per Lowenberg, Musicians Wrestle Everywhere, 13.] "The snake" ["A narrow fellow in the grass"]; "The frog" ["His mansion in the pool"]; "The bee" ["His feet are shod with gauze"]; "The oriole" ["To hear an oriole sing"]; "The spider" ["The spider is an artist"]; "The rat" ["The rat is the concisest tenant"]
    - Blank, Allan, Coalitions, 1975 (Box-folder 7.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Setting for soprano, two clarinets, trombone, piano, two percussionists. (Allan Blank, 2920 Archdale Rd., Richmond, VA 23235). "The heart is the capital of the mind"
    - Bottenberg, Wolfgang, Four Emily Dickinson Songs (Box-folder 8.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Donna Fownes, soprano; Wolfgang Bottenberg, piano. Loyola Chapel, Montreal. May 5, 1983. "The grass so little has to do"; "If I shouldn't be alive"; "A thought went up my mind to-day"; "I taste a liquor never brewed"
    - Convery, Robert, An Amethyst Remembrance: [a song cycle on ten poems of Emily Dickinson] (Box-folder 9.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. "A sepal, petal, and a thorn"; "The bee is not afraid of me"; "I held a jewel in my fingers"; "After great pain, a formal feeling comes"; "To love thee year by year"; "The heart asks pleasure first"; "That first day, when you praised me, sweet"; "The spider is an artist"; "A single clover plank"; "Forbidden fruit a flavor has"
    - Copland, Aaron, Twelve Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 10.)
      Robert Tear, tenor, Philip Ledger, piano. Tape of an LP, Argo, Decca Records, London SW3 6RR; ZRG 862 "Nature, the gentlest mother"; "There came a wind like a bugle"; "Why do they shut me out of Heaven?"; "The world feels dusty"; "Heart, we will forget him"; "Dear March, come in!"; "Sleep is supposed to be"; "When they come back"; "I felt a funeral in my brain"; "I've heard an organ talk sometimes"; "Going to heaven!"; "The chariot"
    - Dal Porto, Mark, Five Pieces for A Cappella Choir: Poems by Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 11.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. "Thoughts of Spring" ["Before you thought of spring"]; "Nature" ["'Nature' is what we see"]; "Morning" ["The sun just touched the morning"]; "Tempest" ["An awful tempest mashed the air"]; "The gentlest mother" ["Nature the gentlest mother is"]
    - The Dickinsingers, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 12.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Side A. Sandra Dejong, soprano; Ann Harper, alto; John Gould, tenor; Hugh Silbaugh, bass. November 1983. "Abraham to kill him" (to "Onward Christian soldiers"); "I took my power in my hands" (to "O God, our help in ages past"); "The red blaze is the morning" (to "The church's one foundation"); "I heard a fly buzz when I died" (to "A mighty fortress is our God") Side B. Sandra DeJong, soprano; Thylias Moss, soprano; Ann Harper, alto; John Gould, tenor; Greg Wilkin, bass; Meredith Price, bass. April 1985. "Let down the bars, Oh death" [Samuel Barber]; From a lecture: "I like to see it lap the miles" (to "I'd Like to Teach the World to Sing")
    - Diemer, Emma Lou, Three Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 13.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Setting for voice and electronic tape. "There came a wind like a bugle" (ca. 7 min.); "Lightly stepped a yellow star" (5 min., 30 sec.); "There is a morn by men unseen" (ca. 7 min.)
    - Foreman, Burton V., Three Emily Dickinson Poems (Box-folder 14.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Melinda Liebermann, soprano; Cornelis Witthoefft, piano. Recorded in Stuttgart, Germany. "I could bring you jewels"; "I many times thought peace had come"; "Sweet is the swamp with its secrets"
    - Getty, Gordon, The White Election (Box-folder 15.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Martha Steiger, soprano; Wendy Glaubitz, piano. Poems by Emily Dickinson, music by Gordon Getty with radio commentary. National Gallery, Washington, DC. May 23, 1982. Part I: The Pensive Spring: "I sing to use the waiting"; "There is a morn by men unseen"; "I had a guinea golden"; "If she had been the mistletoe"; "New feet within my garden go"; "She bore it"; "I taste a liquor never brewed"; "I should not dare to leave my friend"
      Part II: So Must We Meet Apart: "There came a day at summer's full"; "The first day's night had come"; "The soul selects her own society"; "It was not death, for I stood up"; "When I was small, a woman died"; "I cried at pity, not at pain"; "The night was wide"; "I cannot live with you"
      Part III: Almost Peace: "My first well day, since many ill"; "It ceased to hurt me"; "I like to see it lap the miles"; "Split the lark, and you'll find the music"; "The crickets sang"; "After a hundred years"; "The clouds their backs together laid"; "I shall not murmur"
      Part IV: My Feet Slip Nearer: "The grave my little cottage is"; "I did not reach thee"; "My wars are laid away in books"; "There came a wind like a bugle"; "The going from a world we know"; "Upon his saddle sprung a bird"; "Beauty crowds me"; "I sing to use the waiting"
    - Ginsburg, Gerald, Dickinson Songs (Box-folder 16.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) The Music Department of Kean College of New Jersey presents All I Have to Bring: a Celebration of the Poetry of Women / set to music by Gerald Ginsburg. March 3, 1992, Wilkins Theatre, Kean College of New Jersey. Karen Shipp, soprano; Gerald Ginsburg, piano. All I have to bring (1991) / Emily Dickinson. "It's all I have to bring"; "She sweeps with many-colored brooms"; "I never saw a moor"; "Safe in their alabaster chambers"; "I taste a liquor never brewed" [Settings of other poets]
      ii) From The World is a Beautiful Place...: a theatrical/musical experience for soloists and children's chorus with narration / composed and conceived by Gerald Ginsburg. Alice Tully Hall, Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, January 10, 1977. Mary Beth Peil, Rose Taylor, Children's Chorus. "On such a night, or such a night"; "He touched me so I live to know"; "Good morning, midnight"; "To make a prairie"; "The moon was but a chin of gold"; [Settings of other poets]
    - Herberich, Elizabeth, Four Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 17.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Martha Peabody, soprano; John McDonald, piano. Pickman Concert Hall, Cambridge Massachusetts, June 25, 1990. "The grass so little has to do"; "In this short life"; "Soul, take thy risk"; "To break so vast a heart"
  - Cassettes ED 18-34 (Box 21)
    - Hewitt, Harry (Box-folder 18.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) Chartless: Ten Poems of Emily Dickinson. "The grass" ["The grass so little has to do"]; "Autumn" ["The morns are meeker than they were"]; "Evening" ["The crickets sang"]; "I felt a funeral in my brain"; "I never saw a moor"
      ii) Bitters and ballads.
    - Hinkle, Roy B., On God, Love, and Nature (Box-folder 19.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Cycle of five solo songs accompanied by piano. 1982 through 1986. Several performances beginning in 1983. Duration: 11 min., 10 sec. "The moon is distant from the sea"; "A service of song" ["The daisy follows soft the sun"]; "Proof" ["That I did always love"]; "These are the days when birds come back"; "Some keep the Sabbath going to church"
    - Hoiby, Lee, Four Dickinson Songs (Box-folder 20.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Cynthia Miller, soprano; Lee Hoiby, piano. Terrace Theater, Kennedy Center, March 8, 1989. "Wild nights! Wild nights!"; "How the waters closed above him"; "There came a wind like a bugle"; "A Letter" [L261, paragraph 3.]
    - Hoiby, Lee, The Shining Place (Box-folder 21.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. (Five Dickinson songs). Karen Bogan, soprano; Lee Hoiby, piano; Joy in Singing concert, NYC, 1991. "The Shining Place" ["Me come! My dazzled face"]; "A Letter" [L261, paragraph 3]; "How the waters closed"; "Wild nights! Wild nights!"; "There came a wind like a bugle"
    - Højsgaard, Erik, Variations: Six Songs of Autumn (Box-folder 22.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) 1976 version. Anders Ljungar, alto flute; Ulla Rönnborg, cello; Jens Andersen, piano; Marianne Lund, soprano. "I hide myself within my flower" is Variation IV. Includes other poets.
      ii) Fragmenter. 1979 version. Helle Hinz, soprano; Tim Frederiksen, violin; Karl Petersen, guitar. "These saw visions" Includes other poets.
      iii) Two Songs for Mixed Choir. 1985-86. Ars Nova Choir, Bo Holten, conductor. "Not knowing when the dawn will come"; "A sloop of amber slips away"
    - Holab, William, Absence Disembodies (Box-folder 23.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Martin Gonzalez, countertenor; Steven Tritten, tenor; Barry Brandes, bass. May, 1988. "Absence disembodies-so does death"
    - Horvit, Michael (Box-folder 24.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape i) Three songs of elegy. Setting for soprano and piano. "I felt a funeral, in my brain"; "I felt a cleaving in my mind"; Ample make this bed"
      ii) Two Songs for Choir and Electronic Tape. "I heard a fly buzz when I died"; "Because I could not stop for death"
    - Howe, Mary C., Three Pieces after Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 25.)
      Chamber Arts Society of Catholic University of America, Washington, DC (Werner Lywen, George Steiner, violins; Norman Lamb, viola, John Martin, cello) Taped from LP: WCFM LP-9 (1951), copyright by WCFM. "The summers of Hesperides" ["Except the smaller size"]; "Birds by the snow" ["Water, is taught by thirst"]; "God for a frontier" ["I am afraid to own a body" [Inspired by the last line of each poem]
    - Jones, Joseph, Shormies (Box-folder 26.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Recorded early 1991. A selection from several hundred Dickinson poems set to hymn tunes in common meter or long meter. Dickinson poems used in this tape: "I'm nobody. Who are you?"; "A little madness in the spring"; "This was a poet" [spoken]; "Further in summer than the birds"; "As imperceptibly as grief"; "Success is counted sweetest"; "I heard a fly buzz when I died"; "Wild nights! Wild nights!"; "I like to see it lap the miles"; "The brain is wider than the sky"; "Tell all the truth but tell it slant"; "I never saw a moor" [spoken]; "Lightly stepped a yellow star"; "This is my letter to the world"
    - Kalmanoff, Martin, The Joy of Prayer (Box-folder 27.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. [No Emily Dickinson]
    - Kalmanoff, Martin, The Joy of Prayer (Box-folder 28.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. [2nd tape]. [No Emily Dickinson]
    - Kyr, Robert, Maelstrom (Box-folder 29.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Bronwen Mills, soprano; The Fires of London; N. Cleobury, cond. CR02. "Deliberation" ["'Twas like a maelstrom with a notch"]; Elegy (cello solo with instrument); "Ceremony after a fire raid" (Dylan Thomas)
    - Lecture at Syracuse, 1966 (Box-folder 30.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Includes Emily Dickinson.
    - Leich, Roland, Emily Dickinson Songs (Box-folder 31.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. "Of death I try to think like this"; ""When night is almost done"; ""Color, cast, denomination" [solo voice and choral versions]; "I went to heaven"; "Through the strait pass of suffering"; "It tossed and tossed"; "When they come back"; "The butterfly upon the sky"; "To the bright east she flies"; "I'm nobody! Who are you?"; "There came a day at summer's full"; "Because I could not stop for death"; "We talked as girls do"; "Make me a picture of the sun." Sari Bishkoff, mezzo-soprano; Roland Leich, piano
      "As if the sea should part"; "What is paradise?"; "The butterfly upon the sky"; "Mine by the right of the white election"; "You left me, sweet, two legacies"; "Alter? When the hills do." Lynne Webber, soprano; Sara Lee Sax, piano
      "It's all I have to bring today"; ""Because I could not stop for death"; "We do not play on graves"; ""Our share of night to bear"; "I'll tell you how the sun rose"; "I know some lonely houses." Pamela Lewis, mezzo-soprano; Roland Leich, piano
      "I'll tell you how the sun rose"; "Angels in the early morning"; "The butterfly upon the sky"; "Because I could not stop for death"; "I'm nobody. Who are you?"; "When they come back." Carolyn Colton, mezzo-soprano; Gregory Davis, piano
    - Leisner, David (Box-folder 32.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) Simple Songs, 1982. Sanford Sylvan, baritone; David Leisner, guitar. Boston, 1983. "Exultation" ["Exultation is the going"]; "Beauty" ["Beauty crowds me till I die"]; "Madness" ["Much madness is divinest sense"]; "Letter" ["Bee! I'm expecting you"]; "Humility" ["A bee his burnished carriage"]; "Simplicity" ["How happy is the little stone"]
      ii) Confiding, 1985-86. Mary Ann Hart, mezzo soprano; Jon Klibonoff, piano. New York, 1990. "Savior, I've no one else to tell"; "Ample make this bed"; "Wild nights! Wild nights"; "This is my letter to the world." [Includes also poems of Gene Scaramellino, Elissa Ely, and Emily Bronte. ]
    - Lenel, Ludwig, 5 Poems by Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 33.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. "We- -bee and I- -live by the quaffing"; "Of being is a bird"; "Out of sight? What of that?"; "And this of all my hopes"; "Let down the bars, oh death"
    - Mayer, Stephen, Six Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 34.)
      Robert Kuehn, baritone; Stephen Mayer, piano. First performance, Carnegie Recital Hall, 1975. Second performance (revised), Carnegie Recital Hall, June 5, 1987. Written in July 1971; revised April 1986. "Of all the sounds despatched abroad"; "Mine by the right of the white election"; "I reckon when I count at all"; "Of being is a bird"; "Split the lark and you'll find the music"; "Dying at my music"
  - Cassettes ED 35-52 (Box 22)
    - McFarland, Ron (Box-folder 35.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) Emily Dickinson's American Garden Song Book, for soprano and piano, 1985. Sopranos, Maria Ravetti and Barbara Emerson; piano, Ron McFarland "Into my garden come" ["There is another sky"];"The gentian" ["The gentian weaves her fringes"]; "Anemone" ["Summer for thee, grant I may be"]; "Dandelions" ["We should not mind so small a flower"]; "The rose" ["Partake as doth the bee"];"A spider and a flower" ["The fairest home I ever knew"]; "A caterpillar" ["How soft a caterpillar steps"]; "A clover" ["To make a prairie it takes a clover and one bee"]
      ii) A Dickinson Dialogue, for chorus and orchestra. Tamalpais High School Chorus and Orchestra, 1974. "There's a certain slant of light"; "Because I could not stop for death"
      iii) Marinsong for string orchestra. Marin Conservatory Chamber Orchestra, 1991.
      iv) Daughter of Lear, Metropolitan Opera tenor, William Lewis, 1991. (Side B)
    - Morath, Max, In Separate Rooms (Box-folder 36.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Words: Poems by Emily Dickinson. Music: Max Morath, based on rag themes by Scott Joplin. "I'll tell you how the sun rose"; "If you were coming in the fall"; "I never saw a moor" [two versions]
    - Mueter, John. It is a Lonesome Glee: Ten Songs on Poems of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 37.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Jean Herzberg, soprano; John Mueter, piano. Recorded October 1989, White Recital Hall, UMKC Conservatory. "Wild nights! Wild nights!"; "Upon concluded lives"; "I many times thought peace had come"; "The mountains grow unnoticed"; "It is a lonesome glee"; "The wind begun to knead the grass"; "Always mine"; "My best acquaintances are those"; "Here, where the daisies fit my head"; "It was a quiet way"
    - A Musical Evening of Emily Dickinson (Box-folder 38.)
      Performed by Kim Harris, Joshua Peterson, Amanda Hyberger, Judy Cole, William Shomos, Brett Hyberger, Margaret Kennedy-Dygas, William McMullen, Karen Becker, Ann Chang-Barnes, Tyler White, Lanette Lopez, University Chorale, Carolee R. Curtright, Ryan Kasten. Program co-sponsored by the University of Nebraska-Lincoln School of Music and Friends of the UNL Libraries in honor of the Carlton Lowenberg Collection of Emily Dickinson. Materials donated to the UNL Libraries by the Cliffs Charitable Foundation. Kimball Recital Hall, November 24, 1996. I've heard an organ talk sometimes / Aaron Copland; Shining place / Lee Hoiby; Of all the sounds / Dennis Riley; Why do they shut me out of heaven? / Aaron Copland; Sea of sunset; I shall know why / Arthur Farwell; What I can do; Love's stricken 'Why' / Robert Convery; In separate rooms / Max Morath; Route of evanescence / Randall Snyder; An Emily Dickinson mosaic / Daniel Pinkham; Three madrigals for women's chorus / Russell Burnham; Autumn song / Robert Carl; Heart, we will forget him / Mulholland, James.
    - Pender, Scott, From the Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1988 (Box-folder 39.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Setting for SSAA women's chorus, two horns, piano. DaCamera Singers; Ernest Liotti, conductor. (p1989, Scott Pender. All rights reserved. 2441 40th St., NW #2, Washington, DC 20007. (202) 965-1357) Duration: 13 minutes. Letter 225, "The world is just a little place"; letter 234, "The seeing pain one can't relieve"; letter 388, "I hear robins a great way off"; letter 216, "Don't cry, dear Mary."
    - Pilz, Gerhard, The Brain is Wider than the Sky (Box-folder 40.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Setting for guitars, bass, keyboards, drums. Text, Emily Dickinson. (Gerhard Pilz, Gmündmühle 1, A-6914, Hohenweiler, Austria. Tel. and Fax: o5573/4166) "The brain is wider than the sky"
    - Pilz, Gerhard, Rock (Box-folder 41.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape.
    - Saya, Mark, Three, by Emily, 1978 (Box-folder 42.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Lee Francis, soprano; Joel Hoffman, piano. "I'm nobody. Who are you?"; ""To make a prairie it takes a clover and one bee"; "It struck me every day"
    - Sims, JoAnn, That I did always Love (Box-folder 43.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. JoAnn Sims, mezzo; Greg Upton, piano. "That I did always love"
    - Siskind, Paul (Box-folder 44.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. i) Some Epigrams. Complete. Setting for medium or high voice and piano. Mary Law, Kari Paulson, Elizabeth Rodgers, Ted Fitch. Includes Dicksinson song: "I'm nobody. Who are you?"
      ii) Some more epigrams. Complete. Agnes Smuda, John Coonrod. Includes Dickinson song: "I have no life but this"
    - Smit, Leo, piano, A Crazy Quilt of American Piano Music (Box-folder 45.)
      Commercial cassette tape. Musicmasters, 1986. MM40105. The Alcotts: from the "Concord" sonata / Charles Ives. - Hommage a Mozart / Irving Fine. - Three moods. Embittered; Wistful; Jazzy / Aaron Copland. - Dream / John Cage. - Aaron Copland: from "13 portraits for piano" / Virgil Thomson. - Ostinato: from "7 characteristic pieces" / Leo Smit. - Ossian, op. 4, no. 1: ballade / Louis Moreau Gottschalk. - Zero hour / Pete Johnson. - In deep woods, op. 62, no. 5 / Edward MacDowell. - For Lukas Foss: from "5 anniversaries" / Leonard Bernstein. - Adagio: from Sonata no. 2 / Harold Shapero. - A Foggy day / George Gershwin. - Pastoral prelude / Louise Talma. - Whistling tune / Gail Kubik. - In slow blues tempo: from "Excursions," op. 20 / Samuel Barber. - Song of the deathless voice / Arthur Farwell. - Dynamic: from "Three piano moods" / William Schuman.
    - Snyder, Randall, Two Poems (Box-folder 46.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. University of Nebraska Chorus and Wind Ensemble; James Hejduk, conductor. "Hope is the thing with feathers"; "There came a wind like a bugle"
    - This Was a Poet: Emily Dickinson Recalled in Song (Box-folder 47.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. Radio broadcast, KUT-FM, Austin, TX, March 15, 1986. (Script, Joseph Jones; Cina Crisara as Emily Dickinson) Poems read and sung to unidentified hymn tunes. "I'm Nobody. Who are you?"; "A little madness in the spring"; "Further in summer than the birds" (choral); "As imperceptibly as grief" (choral); "Success is counted sweetest" (choral); "I heard a fly buzz when I died"; "Wild nights-Wild nights"; "I like to see it lap the miles"; "The brain is wider than the sky"; "Tell all the truth but tell it slant"; "Lightly stepped a yellow star" (choral); "This is my letter to the world"
    - Vehar, Persis, Emily D. (Box-folder 48.)
      Noncommercial cassette tape. For soprano, flute, oboe and piano. Rachel Lewis, soprano; Marlene Witnauer, flute; Paul Schlossman, oboe; Persis Vehar, piano. "Morning" ["Will there really be a 'morning'?"]; "He stopped for me" ["Because I could not stop for death"]; "For earth, for heaven" ["To help our bleaker parts"]; "Into the beautiful" ["As imperceptibly as grief"]